原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译：草草 辰晓星Reginamoon  Alex  小食人魔 C_C Giggles
翻译：木浅  小僵僵   校对：木浅  某羽
时间轴：念念 吃土少女 Toozii
后期：斯人      总监：木浅
诉 讼 双 雄
第七季   第九集
《诉讼双雄》前情提要
你的上一任男友为什么和你分手
Why'd your last boyfriend break up with you?
他要你在他和哈维之间选择
He asked you to choose between him and Harvey.
-你会选谁  -哈维
- Who'd you choose? - Harvey.
-因为你爱他  -没这么简单
- Because you love him. - It is not that simple.
你有男朋友
You have a boyfriend,
但你的男友不愿意和他共享你
but the one you did wouldn't share you with him.
-法官大人  -拜托  我只是
- Your Honor! - Please, I just need a--
你爱不爱哈维・斯佩克特
Do you love Harvey Specter?!
马克  如果你结婚了
Mark, if you're married,
为什么还答应和我出来吃饭
why did you agree to have lunch with me?
我以为只是普通午餐...
I thought it's just lunch, and--
你很清楚这不只是普通午餐
This hasn't felt like just lunch, and you know it.
你怎么来了
What are you doing here?
我已经在哥伦比亚大学工作六个月了
I've worked at Columbia for the past six months.
我未婚夫住在这里
My fiancé lives in the city,
我想和他在一起
and I wanted to be with him.
我知道怎么阻止弗兰克・加洛作证了
I know how to stop Frank Gallo from testifying.
但我爸不会是唯一一个不喜欢这做法的人
But my dad isn't gonna be the only one who doesn't like it.
-为什么  -因为这涉及到通过我
- Why not? - Because it involves impugning his integrity
质疑他的人品
and doing it through me.
我在周六前都不会返回康涅狄格州
I'm not going back to Connecticut until Saturday.
我未来两天都会住在嘉丽酒店
I'm staying at the Carlyle for the next two nights.
在我结婚之前
I want your body one last time
我想最后要你一次
before I walk down that aisle.
我不是很确定你会来
I didn't know if you'd come.
我做不到
I can't do this.
我不是很确定你会来
I didn't know if you'd come.
我怎么会不来
How could I not?
*看到钱  就愿意留下吃饭*
*See the money, wanna stay for your meal*
*给你太太再拿块馅饼*
*Get another piece of pie for your wife*
*所有人都想知道那感觉*
*Everybody wanna know how it feel*
*所有人都想见见那景象*
*Everybody wanna see what it's like*
*豆子馅饼我也愿吃  我不在乎*
*I'll even eat a bean pie, I don't mind*
*我和妹子忙着赚钱*
*Me and Missy is so busy, busy making money*
*好了*
*All right*
*退开点  我要跳舞*
*All step back, I'm 'bout to dance*
诉讼双雄 第七季 第九集
*美钞爵士摇摇摇*
*The greenback boogie*
小三
Homewrecker.
-什么  -我说可耻
- What? - I said, shame.
可耻  可耻
Shame, shame,
shame, shame
可耻  可耻
shame, shame,
Shame, shame,
可耻  可耻
shame, shame
shame, shame,
可耻  可耻
Shame, shame,
shame, shame
可耻  可耻
shame, shame,
谢天谢地你在
Thank God you are here.
你马上打给利普希茨
I need to call Lipschitz right now
告诉他我今天不能去了  我病了
and tell him I can't make it today, I'm sick.
什么意思  你病了
What do you mean, you're sick?
我病得要死了
I mean I'm deathly ill.
不管他说什么  我都去不了
I can't make it in there no matter what he says.
路易  我无意插手你的事
Louis, I don't mean to get up in your business,
但你去跟那人谈话
but the time you spend with that man
是你这一周中最重要的事
is the most important part of your week.
但我真正的意思是  对我最重要
And by your week, I mean my week.
好吧  我不管是对谁
Okay, I don't care whose week it is,
我今天不能见他  我太忙了
I can't see him today. I'm too busy.
忙  你不是病了吗
Busy. I thought you were sick.
是啊  我又病又忙
I am. Sick and busy.
而且我有一桌的东西要做
And I have a desk full of things I need to get to,
尤其这个
especially this.
你都不知道那是什么
You don't even know what that is.
你好大胆  我很清楚
How dare you. I know what's going on
我桌上每件案子的情况
with every case on my desk.
我只知道这件案子需要我去办
And what I know is this case needs my help.
去打给利普希茨  然后别打扰我
Now, call Lipschitz and leave me to my business
还有
and one more thing:
《权力的游戏》永远不许再上我的待办事项
take "Game of Thrones" off my to-do list for the rest of its run.
布莱恩  我相信不管这是什么案子
Brian, I'm sure you're doing just fine
你都能做的很好
on whatever the hell this case is.
但我就想来问问
But I just thought I'd check in
不管格蕾琴为什么问了起来
and for whatever reason Gretchen happens to ask,
你就这么告诉她
you tell her that's exactly what I did.
好吗  聊天愉快
Okay? Good talk.
其实  是有点问题
Actually, there's a problem with it.
我真的需要你帮忙
And I could really use your help.
-什么问题  -是我们的奶嘴[奶子]
- What's the problem? - It's our nipples.
几乎是完全一样的
They're almost exactly the same.
-什么  -客户  完美宝贝
- Our what now? - Our client, Perfect Baby.
哦  那个奶嘴啊
Yes, those kind of nipples.
不是我今早才...
Not the nipples that I was just this morning--
没事了  你说什么
Never mind. Uh, what were you saying?
我们的奶嘴
There's an overlap between our pacifier
和可爱宝贝要推出的奶嘴有重叠
and the pacifier Sweetie Pie Baby's about to take to market.
我通知了他们  但他们一直在搪塞我
I notified them, but they're giving me the runaround.
所以我想或许如果你打去...
So I thought maybe if you called--
等等  什么意思  搪塞你
Wait, whoa, whoa. What do you mean runaround?
我一直想安排一次会面
I've been trying to set a meeting
都近俩月了  但他们一直拖延
for almost two months, but they keep pushing.
该死的  我们得马上过去
Son of a bitch! We need to get over there right away.
什么  为什么
What? Why?
因为如果我们通知他们有重叠
Because if we notify them of overlap,
但又不在六十天内采取后续行动
but don't follow up within 60 days,
我们将失去起诉他们专利侵权的权利
we lose the right to sue them for patent infringement.
-天啊  -是啊
- Oh, my God. - Exactly.
我们赶紧去告诉那些混蛋
Now let's go tell these assholes
要是他们以为能轻松地剽窃我们的奶嘴
if they think they're gonna rip our nipples off without a fight,
他们就错了
they got another thing coming.
你来干什么  迈克
What are you doing in here, Mike?
我都好几周没机会享受我的早间拿铁了
I haven't had a chance to enjoy my morning latte in weeks.
你见到今早的《周刊》了吗
You seen this morning's "Journal"?
新任副检察长
There's a new Deputy AG.
连赢了15桩案子了
He's won 15 cases in a row.
他立志要整治华尔街
He's making it his mission to clean up Wall Street.
这跟我们有什么关系
What does that have to do with us?
你要去对付他
You're gonna take him on.
什么
Excuse me?
你要跟他打一架
You're gonna pick a fight with this guy,
打破他的不败纪录
and you're gonna clean his clock.
迈克  我感谢你对我能力的信心
Mike, I appreciate your confidence in my ability,
但是  究竟是怎么回事
but... what exactly is going on here?
哈维  我回来时
Harvey, when I got back here,
你立志要向世人证明你不是杰西卡
you set out to show the world that you're not Jessica.
转眼间  我就让你处于防守状态
And three seconds later, I put you on the defensive,
到现在也没有摆脱
and you've been there ever since.
-迈克...  -听我说
- Mike-- - Just listen to me.
乔丹虽然是史上最棒的防守球员
Jordan might've been one of the best defensive players of all time,
但人们并不是因为这个才记住了他
but that's not what people remember him for.
你是说  该我自己控球了
So you're telling me it's time to put the ball in my hands.
我是说  你去挑战这个大能人
I'm telling you that you take on this hotshot,
就能让世界知道  你想对付谁都行
you show the world that you can take on anyone.
这是个好点子  迈克
That's a great idea, Mike,
只是  他并没有找我们任何客户的麻烦
but the only problem is, he's not coming after any of our clients,
我希望你不是建议我们送一个给他当目标
and I hope you're not suggesting we put one of them on his radar.
我是说我们去签一个本就是他目标的客户
I'm saying we sign a client that's already on his radar.
你怎么不早说呢
Why the hell didn't you say that in the first place?
我不需要说  我已经签了
I didn't need to, 'cause I already signed them.
那我们去会会那个混蛋
Then I guess we pay this jerkoff a visit
告诉他  他的不败纪录要破了
and let him know his winning streak just came to an end.
我本打算在这种地方买会员的
You know, I was thinking about joining a place like this.
但是
The truth is,
我从来讨厌一群废柴在一个封闭空间里
I've never been a fan of losers sweating together
一起流汗
in a confined space.
除非是在法庭上  而且是你让他们流汗
Unless it's in a courtroom and you're the one making them sweat.
看来我名声远播
I see my reputation precedes me.
我现在清楚你的名声了  斯佩克特
Well, I'm aware of your reputation now, Specter.
不如你赶紧说你此行的目的吧
So why don't you tell me what the hell you're doing here?
那你应该也知道我不喜欢浪费时间
Then you're also aware that I don't like to waste my time
或者我客户的钱
or my client's money.
所以不如你马上放弃
So why don't you drop your bullshit case
对埃尔蒙特投资的扯淡诉讼
against Elmont Investments right now?
你什么时候开始代理埃尔蒙特投资了
Since when are you representing elmont Investments?
他们发现某人为了给自己贴金要坑他们
Since they realized they were being railroaded by a showboater
所以想找个真正的律师叫那人知道厉害
and that they needed a real lawyer to put him in his place.
-是吗  -是的
- Is that a fact? - Yes, it is.
在我看来你还得带上你的小跟班
Well, it looks to me you had to bring your little buddy here
就是因为怕得不敢一个人来见我
because you're too scared to go up against me by yourself.
他不怕任何人的
Yeah, he's not really scared of anyone.
而且告诉你  10分钟前
And for your information, until about 10 minutes ago,
他还不知道你是谁
he had no idea who you were.
扯淡  他很清楚我是谁
Bullshit. He knows exactly who I am.
我们在同一个办公室干了三年
We worked in the same damn office for three years
什么
What?
你说什么呢
What the hell are you talking about?
你真不记得我了  是吗
You really don't remember me, do you?
不记得
No, I don't.
那我提醒你一下
Well let me ring a bell for you.
我叫安德鲁・马利克
My name is Andrew Malik.
你去讨好卡梅隆・丹尼斯
And while you were kissing Cameron Dennis's ass
处理大案时  我在隔了三个门的办公室里
working on high profile cases, I was three doors down,
干到凌晨两点
working till two in the morning
把真正的罪犯送入监狱
putting the real criminals away.
你当时可能没记住我
And you may not have remembered me then,
但你这次绝对会记住我的
but you're sure as hell going to remember me now.
十二年前
你在这里干什么
What are you doing in here?
没什么  哈维让我把这个放卡梅隆桌上
Nothing. Harvey asked me to put this on Cameron's desk.
当然了
Of course he did.
卡梅隆和哈维简直和父子一样
Cameron and Harvey are like father and son.
而你和哈维就像是...
And you and Harvey are like--
你懂的
Well, you know what.
说实话我还真不懂  你说说看
No, I don't, actually. Why don't you tell me?
当我没说
Forget it.
我不打算当你没说  安德
I'm not gonna forget it, Andy.
你不能随随便便做这种错误的指控
And I'm not gonna let you make a false accusation like that
然后一走了之
and get away with it.
那这个指控也是错误的吗
How about this accusation?
现在已经八点多了  我还在这里工作
It's past eight, and I'm still here working.
但卡梅隆不会知道
Cameron will never see that
因为他八成和你老板出去喝酒了
because he's probably out getting a drink with your boss.
那也许你该意识到
Well then maybe you should realize
努力工作并不是生命中的唯一
that working hard isn't the only thing that matters in life.
不  真正重要的是一个人得关心自己的工作
No, what should matter is that you care about what you do.
卡梅隆爱哈维
And Cameron loves Harvey.
所以他看不清摆在他面前的事实
So he can't see the truth that's in front of his face.
什么事实
And what truth is that?
哈维・斯佩克特不会一直留在这里
That there is no way that Harvey Specter will be here forever.
但我会
Well, I'll be here forever.
而我不在乎他俩的关系有多密切
And I don't care how tight they are
也不在乎你俩的关系有多密切
or how tight the two of you are.
我在检察官这个职位上会比你们干的都久
I will outlast you all as a prosecutor.
你在这儿呢
There you are.
我到处找你
I was looking all over for you.
怎么了
What for?
我知道你不想多谈你昨晚的约会
Well I know you were being a little secretive about your date last night.
但我关心你
But I care about you
我想知道情况如何
and I wanted to know how it went.
没情况
It didn't.
-你不是说...  -我知道我说了什么
- But you said-- - I know what I said.
我想自我感觉良好一晚
I wanted a night to just feel good about myself.
但我意识到昨晚不是时候
But I realized that last night wasn't gonna do that.
所以我取消了
So I called it off.
我很遗憾
Sorry.
你想谈谈吗
You wanna talk about it?
不  瑞秋  我不想
No, Rachel. I don't.
抱歉  你们是不是走错办公室了
I'm sorry, I think you have the wrong office.
我们没走错
Oh, we're in the right office.
实际上  我们三周前就应该见面的
In fact, we were supposed to meet three weeks ago,
但你要求另约时间  结果一直没约
but you asked to reschedule and never did.
你是皮尔逊-斯佩克特律所的人
You're from Pearson Specter.
皮尔逊-斯佩克特-利特
Pearson Specter Litt.
布莱恩和我说
And according to Brian,
他一直试图约你见面  但都没成功
he's been trying to meet with you for quite some time.
对  我们一直挺忙的  所以...
Yes, we've been a bit busy, so--
可不是嘛  忙着抢我们客户的钱
Yeah, busy trying to douche our client out of their money.
你要以为我们会放任你们的盗版奶嘴流入市场
And if you think we're letting you go to market with your rip-off nipple,
那你简直比那些买你的破尿布的婴儿还傻
you're even dumber than the babies that buy your crappy diapers.
我们不会把我们的新产品撤下市场的
We're not shelving our new product.
那样的话  我们会起诉你们
In that case, we'll take you to court,
你的产品最终还是会被撤下
and it'll end up being shelved anyway.
或者你们可以承认侵犯了我们的设计
Or you can admit you infringed on our design
然后给我们你们收益的60%
and cut us in for 60%.
我们什么都没有侵犯
We didn't infringe on anything
假如你觉得我们侵犯了
and if you think we did
那你完全不了解你所代理的市场
then you don't know a thing about the market you represent.
不了解市场
Not know the market?
告诉你  我家刚添了宝宝
For your information, I've got a newborn.
要不是有我们的奶嘴
And if it weren't for our pacifiers,
我上个月基本上就不用睡了
I wouldn't have gotten what little sleep I have in the last month.
那我猜你当父亲比你当律师更不称职
Then I guess you're an even shittier father than you are a lawyer
因为假如不用奶嘴你就不能哄宝宝入睡
because if you can't put a baby down without a pacifier,
那你在庭上完全没胜算
then you don't have a chance in hell against us in court.
你说什么
What did you just say?
我说无论是作为父亲还是作为律师
I said you don't know what you're doing
你都不知道自己在做什么
as a father or a lawyer.
你怎么敢这么说  我不管你怎么想的
How dare you. I don't give a shit what you think.
我们不要那60%
We're not taking 60%.
我们要把你们告个底朝天
We're gonna sue your ass into the ground.
等下我一回到办公室
And as soon as I get back to my office,
我就要申请限制令
I'm filing a restraining order
永远地阻止你那假货流入市场
to stop you from ever taking your fraudulent product to market,
你个大骗子
you lying sack of shit.
好了  说说你在想什么吧
All right, why don't you say what's on your mind?
谁说我在想事情了
Who says there's anything on my mind?
你永远都在想事情
There's always something on your mind.
只有在你不确定自己应不应该说的时候
The only time it doesn't pop right out of your mouth
你才会闭嘴不谈你的想法
is when you're not sure you should say it.
听着  我刚刚就是在想
Look, I was just thinking
假如我早知道你和这家伙有过节
if I'd known there was a personal history with this guy,
我就不会选这个案子了
I wouldn't have picked this case.
是啊  假如我早知道我和这个家伙有过节
Yeah, if I'd known there was a personal history with this guy,
就不用等你替我选了
you wouldn't have had to.
哈维  听我说
Harvey, listen to me.
我接了监狱那个案子  差点让我们关门
I took on the prison case and it almost ripped us apart.
我接这个案子就是为了弥补
I took on this to make up for that.
我可不希望这个案子和监狱那个一样
I don't want it to do the same thing.
你为什么会觉得自己知道这个案子的后果
What makes you think you know what this case is gonna do?
我并不知道这个案子会造成什么后果
I don't know exactly what it's gonna do.
但我知道这案子涉及个人恩怨
But I know it's personal with this guy
这种情况通常没有好下场
and that never ends well.
我们依然有机会退出
You still have time to get out.
迈克说得对  哈维
Mike's right, Harvey.
你不会想和这人对着干的
You do not wanna go up against this man.
我甚至都不记得这个人
I don't even remember this guy.
你还指望我临阵退缩吗
You expect me to run scared?
我可记得他
Well I remember him.
三年来你表现得像是这人不存在一样
You acted like he didn't exist for three years.
但他很卑鄙  且诡计多端
But he is sneaky and he is conniving
更别提如今他有检察院在背后支持
and now he's got the power of the AG's office behind him.
我不在乎他背后有谁
I don't care what office he has.
他记得我而我不记得他的唯一原因就是
The only reason he remembers me and I don't remember him
他很烂  而我很棒
is he sucked and I was awesome.
假如你跟我说几年下来
And if you're telling me that between then and now
我止步不前而他突飞猛进  我可不买账
I've stalled and he's skyrocketed, I'm not buying it.
我觉得唐娜是想说  这家伙就像是
I think what Donna's trying to say is that this guy
路易・利特和艾略特・斯坦普尔的合体
is like Louis Litt and Elliott Stemple rolled into one.
和这种人  能避免交战就该尽量避免
And if you can avoid a fight with him, you should.
我们之间必有一战
Well, I can't avoid a fight with him
因为刚刚是我们挑起了战争
because we just picked one.
不管你俩怎么想的
And despite what you both seem to think,
我能对付得了他
I can handle him.
你马上就有机会对付他了
Well, you're gonna get your chance.
因为他刚刚传讯了我们的客户
'Cause he just subpoenaed our new client.
路易  我很抱歉
Louis, I'm so sorry.
我一不小心就失控了
I didn't mean to fly off the handle like that.
什么  你在逗我吗
What? Are you kidding?
这是我这周经历的最棒的事了
That was the best thing I've seen in weeks.
所以...你不生我的气
So...you're not mad?
生气  我完全被镇住了
Mad? I'm blown away.
感觉看到了一只凶狠霸气的蝴蝶
It was like watching a fierce, manly butterfly
从它又娘又小的茧里破茧而出
emerge from its pussy little cocoon.
那个布莱恩是从哪冒出来的
Where the hell did that Brian come from?
我也说不清  我猜你说我什么都可以
I don't know. I guess you can say a lot of things about me,
但你一旦侮辱我当父亲的能力...
but when you insult my ability as a father--
就能唤醒你心中的雄狮
It brings out the lion in you.
之类的吧
Something like that.
但我保证  这种情况不会再发生了
But I promise, it won't happen again.
但我希望它能再次发生
But I want it to happen again.
实际上  你起草那份限制令的时候
In fact, when you draft the restraining order,
我想让你想象那个混蛋
I want you picturing that asshole
和他朋友说笑你是个多么糟糕的父亲
laughing to his buddies about what a shitty father you are.
写开庭陈述时想想这些
Think about it when you're writing the opening,
写到一半时想想这些
think about it in the middle,
写结案陈词时也要想一想
and definitely think about it when you write the close.
因为从今往后  我只要狮王布莱恩
Because Mufasa Brian is the only Brian I want to see from now on.
《狮子王》中辛巴的父亲
我们抓紧时间  我客户可是很忙的
Let's get on with this. My client's a busy woman.
很显然她忙到竟没觉察到
Apparently she's too busy to realize
她雇了一家会出卖自己客户的律所
she just hired a firm that's willing to sell out their own clients.
你什么意思
What the hell are you talking about?
别装了
Oh, come on.
你肯定知道威廉・萨特的下场了
You must be aware of what happened with William Sutter.
事实是在那种情况下
What happened was Harvey got him a better deal
哈维帮他达成的协议不能更好了
than anyone could have under the circumstances.
把他送进监狱里面  这是个好协议吗
Is that what you call sending him to prison? A great deal?
但愿你除了翻翻我们公司老账
I hope there's more to your legal strategy
还有其他法律策略  安德
than talking shit about my firm, Andy.
看来你去找人打听我了
Oh, I see you asked someone who I was.
好不容易才找到个还记得你的人
Took a while to find someone who actually remembered.
现在向我客户提问吧
Now ask my client an actual question
否则会面马上终止
or I'm shutting this down right now.
好  那我就问一个
Okay, here's one:
斯坦格夫人  跟我说说你为何12月31日
Mrs. Stanger, why don't you tell me why one of your divisions
下午11点53突然将一个部门售出
suddenly needed to be sold on December 31st at 11:53 P.M.?
我们达成了盼望已久的协议
We finally got the offer that we'd been waiting for.
这份协议比上次谈判少了8百万
An offer worth 8 million less than the last one.
没记错的话  副检察长
Last time I checked, being a Deputy AG
也不是批发海运的专家
doesn't make you an expert in wholesale shipping.
没错  但我的确是
No, but it sure as hell makes me an expert
高管非法锁定奖金的专家
on executives locking in their bonuses illegally.
-不是这  -他在引诱你  别回答
- That is not-- - He's baiting you. Don't respond.
我没有引诱她  我在取证
I'm not baiting. I'm deposing.
那你为什么不问些有真凭实据的问题
Then why don't you ask a goddamn question based on evidence
把你的长篇大论留在法庭以外
and save your speeches for outside the courthouse?
你是否有意欺骗你的股东
Did you knowingly defraud your shareholders
-来增加自己的奖金  -别回答
- to inflate your own bonus? - Don't answer that.
那你有没有告知董事会
Did you inform your board of directors
你以低价达成协议
that you were taking a below market offer?
也别回答
Don't answer that either.
你们有很多不能回答的问题
Wow, you're getting a lot of, "Don't answer that question."
我明白为什么他们这么值钱了
I can see why they're worth the big bucks.
听着  混蛋  我的客户是清白的
Listen to me, asshole. My client's innocent.
你除了含沙射影什么证据也没有
And you come at her with nothing but innuendo,
她要用《第五修正案》
she's taking the 5th.
我来告诉你些从你不当检察官以后
Well, let me tell you something that you may not know
你可能不知道的事
since you left being a prosecutor:
清白的人不会引用《第五修正案》
innocent people never take the 5th.
你要引用  我就把刑事案放一边
And if you try that, I'll put the criminal case on hold,
我会把董事会弄上民事指控
I'll bring the board up on civil charges
相信我  在我给他们开条件之前
and believe me, they will roll over on her
他们就会向她倒戈的
before I'm finished offering them the chance.
-他能这么做吗  -没错  我能
- Can he do that? - Yes, I can.
而且  你清不清白我根本不在乎
And for the record, i don't give a shit if you're innocent or not.
你就要坐牢了
You are going to prison.
这样印象够深刻了吧  哈维
How's that for making an impression, Harvey?
爸
Dad.
你来干什么
What are you doing here?
刚好路过
I was in the neighborhood.
我想到从你当上律师以后
I realized I haven't seen your office
我还没来过你办公室
since you became a member of the bar.
很高兴你这么说  但我办公室一点没变
Well, that's sweet but my office hasn't changed one bit
所以你还是告诉我你来的真实意图
so why don't you tell me what you're really doing here?
我来是要告诉你那步棋你走的很险
I came to tell you that was one hell of a move you made,
在改造公司案上用我女儿来对付我
using my own daughter against me with the Reform Corp. Case.
我不仅是你的女儿  我是名律师
I'm not just your daughter. I'm a lawyer.
这正是我此行的目的  我想和你共事
That's why I'm here. I wanna work with you.
我没听懂
I don't follow.
瑞秋  弗兰克・加洛想改善和他女儿的关系
Rachel, Frank Gallo wanted to connect with his daughter
一直等到错过了机会
and waited until it was too late.
我可不想犯同样的错误
I don't wanna make that same mistake.
我很高兴你这么说  爸
And I appreciate that, Dad.
但是我也说的很清楚了
But I've also made it really clear
我想按自己的方式来
that I wanna make my own way.
我不是想让你换律所
Oh, I'm not talking about you switching firms.
我说的是个无偿案
I'm talking about a pro bono.
我知道你去年和杰西卡做过一个
Now I know you did one with Jessica last year,
我想是时候你和我也能做一个
I thought maybe it was time you did one with me.
-什么案子  -掠夺性贷款
- What kinda case? - Predatory lending.
占有色人种的便宜
Taking advantage of people of color.
我很乐意
I'd really like that.
但是我得先跟哈维说清楚
But I have to clear it with Harvey first.
不用了  我告诉他我想和我的家人共事
No, you don't. I told the man I wanted to work with my family
他说  "当然可以  罗伯特
and he said, "Of course, Robert.
这种事我非常赞同"
How can I stand in the way of that?"
这样的话
Well, in that case.
我觉得我们应该去你办公室一趟
I think we should head back to your office
做好准备让这些混蛋瞧瞧
and get ready to show those bastards
赞恩父女联手有多厉害
what the team of Zane and Zane can do.
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
不  不用  我刚和最后一个董事
No, we don't. I just got off the phone
通完电话
with the last board member.
我们得把他们聚到一起
We need to get 'em in a room
在马利克找到机会递传票前
and lock 'em down before Malik
先把他们稳住
gets a chance to issue subpoenas.
哈维  你听到他的话了  这不够
Harvey, you heard him. It's not gonna be enough.
-你在说什么  -我是说趁来得及
- What are you saying? - I'm saying that we cut a deal
我们付钱达成协议
to pay a fine while we still can.
-你在开玩笑吗  -听我说
- Are you kidding me? - Listen to me,
我看到那女人脸上的表情了
I saw the look on that woman's face.
她确实做了  董事会会知道的
She did it, and the board's gonna know it.
只要他把这事弄上民事法庭
The second that he makes this civil,
他们就会向她倒戈  如他所言
they're gonna turn on her, just like he said.
我明白怎么回事了
I get what this is.
你什么意思
What the hell are you talking about?
你想用这个案子补偿
You brought me this to make up
你在无偿案上
for your pro bono fixation
对我捣的乱
messing with my business.
现在你发现她是有罪的
And now you found out that she's guilty,
你想一走了之  因为这有违你的准则
so you wanna cut and run 'cause it goes against your code.
不是这样的
That's bullshit.
我和她签约时就知道她不是清白的
I knew she was guilty the second I signed her.
哈维  我们讨论的不是
Harvey, we're not talking about
什么化学公司引发了癌症
some chemical company causing cancer.
我们谈论的是一个有钱人
We're talking about one rich person
从另外的有钱人身上偷钱
stealing money from other rich people.
我建议达成协议是因为他确实有我们的把柄
I'm saying that we cut a deal because he's got us.
她没给他留下任何把柄
He doesn't have shit because she didn't give him anything.
这对他都无关紧要
That doesn't matter to him
对陪审团也不重要
and it's not gonna matter to a jury
因为不管我们怎么想  她都有罪
because she's guilty whether we like it or not.
-你刚刚在说什么  -我说她是有罪的
- What did you just say? - I said she's guilty.
不  你说这对他来说并不重要
No, you said it doesn't matter to him.
但是她对他并不重要  我们有他
But she doesn't matter to him and we got him
承认的录影带
on tape admitting it.
马利克不止是公司律师
Malik's not just some corporate lawyer.
他还是个公务员
He's a public servant.
我记得  公务员
And last I checked, public servants
必须在意被告是否有罪
are supposed to give a shit if someone's guilty or not.
天哪  解决他了
Holy shit. We've got him.
斯诺思琪女士  我叫瑞秋・赞恩
Ms. Sonowski? My name's Rachel Zane,
这是我父亲罗伯特・赞恩
this is my father Robert Zane.
我们约好了吗
Did we have an appointment?
因为我今天行程很满
Because I have a full schedule today.
那你就得因为这桩官司把行程都推掉
Then you're gonna have to clear it because this lawsuit
这已变成你的头等大事了
just became your number one priority.
种族歧视诉讼  真不敢相信
A discrimination suit. This is unbelievable.
让人不敢相信的是
What's unbelievable is that your bank
你的银行以为自己可以多年来剥削客户
thought they could rip people off for years
-而不被人发现  -我猜猜  你要
- without anyone noticing. - Let me guess, you're gonna
用这东西侮辱我一番
slap me with this and turn around
然后转身就要求和解
and 15 seconds later tell me you wanna settle.
我什么都不想和解
I don't wanna settle anything.
我要对你们的总裁取证
I wanna depose your CEO.
这是不可能发生的
Well, that's not gonna happen.
怎么不可能  这是合法的诉讼
Bullshit, it's not. This is a legitimate lawsuit.
我们还是跳过
Then why don't we skip the part
这个互相攻击的阶段
where you punch me and I counterpunch you
直接告诉我你能接受的底价吧
and you go ahead and give me your bottom line number right now.
一
One.
-一什么  -一个
- One what? - One son of a bitch
专门压榨别人的混蛋
who's been screwing over people.
这就是我的底价
That's my number.
我想要这个混蛋低头认罪
And I want the man's head on a platter.
那我们就法庭见吧
Then I guess I'll see you in court.
因为我不会让你
Because I'm not gonna let you
那么轻易就取证我的上司
depose my boss without a fight.
先生们  你们为什么来这里
Okay, gentlemen, why exactly are we here?
法官大人  我们来这里的原因是
Your Honor, we're here because this is
这是一起捏造的控诉  不应进行下去
a trumped up charge that shouldn't be allowed to go forward.
如果真的是捏造的
If it's so trumped up,
你的委托人为什么
why wouldn't your client answer
-拒绝回答任何问题  -因为她的工作是
- a single question about it? - Because it's her job
保护自己的公司  而不是提供
to protect her company, not offer up information
-不利于公司的信息  -扯淡
- to be used against it. - Bullshit.
你的委托人只想保护她自己的红利
All your client cares about is protecting her bonus.
而你只想
And all you care about
让自己出名
is making a name for yourself
即使是以陷害无辜的人为代价
even if it means taking down innocent people.
斯佩克特先生  你这样
Mr. Specter, I'd think very carefully
指控一位副检察长
before accusing a Deputy Attorney General
-需要谨慎  -我不是在指控他
- of something like that. - I'm not accusing him
法官大人
of anything, Your Honor.
我在逐字重复
I'm repeating exactly
他对我的委托人说的话  有录音为证
what he told my client on tape.
什么  你在说谎
What? That's a lie.
你想听一下录音吗
You want us to play it for you?
我们录下了他说的话
We have him on tape saying
他说他根本不在乎珍妮特・斯坦格
he doesn't give a shit whether Janet Stanger
-是不是无辜的  -法官大人
- is innocent or not. - Your Honor,
那只是我一时冲动说的话
that was said in the heat of the moment.
-我不是那么想的  -你是说  你那么说
- I did not mean that literally. - You mean you only said it
只是为了恐吓我的客户
to intimidate my client.
-那不是恐吓  -那到底是什么
- It wasn't intimidation. - Then what the hell was it?
-你这个人渣  -马利克先生
- You piece of shit. - Mr. Malik.
我很欣赏你在华尔街的工作
I like what you've been doing for Wall Street.
但我不会允许你为了展现个人成绩
But I'm not letting you prosecute a fabricated case
而在我的法庭上进行这种捏造的控告
in my courtroom just to get another notch in your belt.
我没有那么做
That's not what I'm doing.
给你24小时时间  证明他们错了
Then you have 24 hours to prove them wrong.
我建议你别再继续骂人
So I suggest you stop calling them names
赶紧给自己的案子找点证据
and go find yourself some evidence.
希拉・赛兹
路易  小气鬼婴儿用品那家的混蛋在一号线上
Louis, that asshole from Cheapskate Baby is on line one.
-路易  -你说什么
- Louis. - What'd you say?
我说那个坑骗我们委托人的混蛋
I said that sucker that's trying to rip off
给你打电话了
our client's calling.
明显他收到布莱恩的临时禁制令了
Evidently, he got Brian's TRO.
那他可要大哭一场了
Which means he's about to cry his eyes out.
这正是我所需要的  他在几号线来的
This is just what I needed. What line did you say?
一号
One.
汉克  看来你已经收到临时禁制令了
Hank, I understand you got our TRO.
-没错  -我估计你打电话是为了
- I sure as hell did. - But I assume you're calling
求我不要让你们的产品全军覆没
to beg me to let you keep a piece of your product.
哥们  很抱歉  这是不可能的
Well, sorry to tell you, buddy. That's not gonna happen.
你怎么没哭呢
Why don't I hear crying?
你的新律师把禁制令送过来之前
You didn't read that thing before your associate
你都没读过吧
sent it over, did you?
我当然读过
Well, of course I read it.
哪有白痴把文件送过去之前
What kind of idiot doesn't read a document
自己读都不读
before sending it over?
就有这样的白痴  为我们的反诉
The kind that just opened the door for us
帮了个大忙
to countersue the shit out of him.
因为他正忙着惦记某个
Because he was too busy thinking about the woman
不可能嫁给他的女人
he's never going to marry.
-你刚说什么  -我说我是希拉的未婚夫
- What did you just say? - I said, I'm Sheila's fiancé
我知道你跟她睡过
and I know you slept with her.
现在  你还正在想着鬼鬼祟祟地...
And even now you're thinking about sneaking around and--
你不懂  这只是...
You don't understand, it was just--
仅此一次
A one-time thing?
你差点把我这辈子毁了
You could've ruined my life
你这个自私的混蛋
you selfish son of a bitch.
但我爱希拉  如果你以为
But I love Sheila, so if you think
这就能阻止她嫁给我  你就错了
this is gonna stop us from getting married, it's not.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我不是有意的
I didn't mean to.
你是不是有意的并不重要
It doesn't matter whether you meant it or not.
你要以为这能阻止我们的产品投入市场
If you think this is gonna stop us from going to market,
那你就连那个
you're an even shittier lawyer
愧为律师的菜鸟都不如
than that sorry excuse for an associate.
-你好  路易  -别跟我说你好
- Louis, hey. - Don't hey me.
-是你提交的临时禁制令吗  -是
- Did you file that TRO? - Yeah.
-早上一来就交了  -你提交之前读了吗
- First thing this morning. - And did you read it before you did?
当然
Of course.
那你是文盲吗
Then what are you, illiterate?
你送过去了一份禁制令  上面写着
Because that's the only reason I can think of
"他们的产品比不上我们的"
as to why you'd send a restraining order
只有文盲才会这么干
that says their product's inferior to ours.
-什么  -对  "比不上"
- What? - That's right, inferior.
比不上就是不一样
As in, different.
不  我不可能用了这个词
No, I couldn't have used that word.
看来你是世界上最烂的律师  因为你确实
Well, you could've if you're the world's worst lawyer,
用了这个词
which you apparently are.
这整个案子都被你搞砸了
Because you just invalidated our whole goddamn case.
因为不同的产品不可能
Because if they're different, they couldn't have
-侵犯专利  -路易  我真的很抱歉
- violated our patent. - Okay, Louis, I am so sorry.
你让我想着他嘲笑我的样子  想着他说
You told me to think of that guy laughing
-我是个不称职的父亲  -你是说这怪我
- and how bad a father I was-- - Are you saying this is my fault?
不是...
No, I--
这不怪我  这都是你的错
Because this is not my fault, this is your fault.
我知道  我真的很抱歉
I know. I am so sorry.
免了  你别参与这个案子了
No. What you are is off this case.
-拜托  路易  -不  你给我闭嘴
- Louis, please. - No. You shut the hell up!
我们的委托人把特别而珍爱的东西
Our client trusted you with something special,
委托给你
with something they love.
而你在他们背后
And then you snuck around behind their back
做了愚蠢而不计后果的事情
and you did something stupid and reckless.
你毁掉了他们的生活
And you ruined their life,
你这个一文不值的自私的混蛋
you worthless, selfish son of a bitch!
法官大人  这家银行存在掠夺性贷款的行为
Your Honor, this bank has a practice of predatory lending.
这种行为自上而下
It starts at the top and we can end
我们可以取证他们的总裁  结束这一切
this whole thing quickly by deposing their CEO.
他们想速战速决  因为他们没有证据
They need to end this quickly because they have nothing.
要是每次律师申请  我的就要接受取证
And if every time a lawyer wanted to sit down my client
他就没法工作了
and depose him, he'd never be able to do his job.
多棒的论据  "你们不能对他取证
What a wonderful argument. "You can't depose us,
因为我们正忙着压榨客户"
because we're too busy screwing over our clients."
赞恩先生  如果你需要对一位重要人士取证
Mr. Zane, if you wanna tie up an important man
使其长达几小时无法正常工作
for hours on end, you need to show
你要有足够的证据作为支撑
there's enough evidence to warrant it.
我会给出证据的  法官大人
I'll give you evidence, Your Honor.
我们会把约翰・富勒资料上交陪审团
We'll show the jury John Fuller,
他每年赚取八万美金而且也有自己的事业
who makes $80,000 a year and has his own business.
此外我们也会提交梅格・格罗斯曼的资料
And then we'll show them Meg Grossman,
年收入相同但信用卡债务数额与其持平
who makes the same but has at least that much
-甚至更大  -而后我们会询问陪审团
- in credit card debt. - And then we'll ask the jury
谁更有可能获得条件更好的抵押贷款
who they would give the better mortgage to.
我们敢保证12名陪审员都会选富勒先生
And we're willing to bet that all 12 would pick Mr. Fuller.
而要不是他是非裔美国人的话
Which is who his bank would've picked
他的银行也应当作出同样选择的
if he weren't African American.
法官大人  他们挑出的是两个个案
Your Honor, they're picking two cases.
-一百个里选了两个  -我确信这可以找到解释
- Two out of 100. - And I'm sure there's an explanation.
那让你该死的总裁过来解释
Then get your goddamn CEO in here to give it.
够了  赞恩先生
That's enough, Mr. Zane.
我同意让你立案
I'm willing to let you build a case,
但要让我支持你的指责
but I need evidence your claims are true
你需要提供证据来证明其真实性
before I'm gonna let you figure out who to blame.
-法官大人  -你可以首先
- Your Honor-- - You can start
让相关的信贷员出庭作证
by deposing the loan officers.
但除非证据充足到足以立案
But unless there's enough there to make a case,
你只能到此为止
that's all you're gonna get.
格蕾琴  你在这里干什么  出去
Gretchen, what the hell are you doing here? Get out.
我不出去
I'm not going anywhere.
你无权如此对待那孩子
You had no business treating that boy like that.
你知道吗  如果你准备
Well, you know what? If all you're gonna do
对我指手画脚  在我看来
is judge me, as far as I'm concerned,
布莱恩不是唯一能逃过被解雇的幸运儿
Brian's not the only one lucky not to be fired.
-你刚对我说什么  -你没听错
- What did you say to me? - You heard me.
走开  否则你就等着卷铺盖走人吧
Back off or you're gone.
那你最好听着
Then you better hear this:
你说过他们都是你的孩子
you say those kids are your children.
而父亲不会那样对待他的孩子
Well, a father doesn't treat his children that way.
你知道你在说些什么吗
You don't know what you're talking about.
我不知道个鬼
The hell I don't!
你暴躁易怒  口出恶言
You were nasty and abusive.
如果他真的是你的儿子  我会马上
And if he were your son, I'd be calling
-报告儿童服务机构  -但他不是
- Child Services right now. - Well, he's not my son!
他是一名律师  而且这不关你的事
He's a lawyer and this is none of your goddamn business.
不关我的事
None of my business?
照顾你的人和工作就是我的事
Watching your back is my goddamn business.
我不知道发生了什么
I don't know what the hell is going on
让你不愿和利普希茨谈一谈
with you that you don't wanna talk to Lipschitz about,
但你最好给我好好处理这事
but you better get a handle on it.
因为如果你也这样对待其他的律师
Because if you treat another associate like that,
我会好好教训你
I will knock you the hell out.
现在就举杯庆祝胜利不会太早了吗
Isn't it a little early for a victory drink?
你看见马利克的表情了吗
Did you see the look on Malik's face?
要我说这酒已经迟了几小时了
I'd say we're a couple of hours late.
那我想我也得和你喝一杯了
Then I guess I better join you.
因为到明天  华尔街得所有人都会知道
'Cause by tomorrow, all of Wall Street's gonna know
安迪・马利克和皮尔逊・斯佩克特・利特作对
that Andy Malik went up against Pearson Specter Litt
而且还破天荒地输了
and lost in record time.
迈克  谢谢你交给我这起案子
Thanks for bringing me this case, Mike.
别客气  哈维  我还想说
You're welcome, Harvey. And for the record,
抱歉我之前说你应该认输
I'm sorry I said you should've thrown in the towel.
没关系  我也很抱歉你这么说了
It's okay. I'm sorry you said it, too.
再多给我来一杯  我也想庆祝了
Got an extra glass? I feel like celebrating, too.
马利克  你在这里干什么
What are you doing here, Malik?
我是来这里给你们这个的
I'm here to deliver this.
是什么
What's that?
是明天的报纸
It's a copy of tomorrow's paper.
我必须递交所有的证据  不像你
I'm required to hand over all discovery and unlike you,
-我照着要求做了  -这是什么意思
- I comply with that requirement. - What's that supposed to mean?
你明天就会知道了
Oh, you'll find out what it means tomorrow.
那为什么你今晚特意过来一趟
Then why did you come all the way down here
把报纸给我们
to give us this tonight?
因为我想在我反败为胜的时候
Because I wanted to see the look on your face
能观摩到你们脸上的表情
when I told you that I've got you,
你这个混球
you cocky son of a bitch.
如果你想打开录音设备
Oh, and if you wanna turn on your recorder,
尽管开  我会对着
go right ahead, 'cause I'll say that
镜头来说
right to the camera.
晚安  先生们  享用你们的酒吧
Good night, gentlemen. Enjoy your drinks.
唐娜  我发现你总是处于同样的处境
Donna. I see you're in the same position as you always were.
我发现你和哈维一样总是
And I see you have the same Harvey-sized
总是爱找麻烦
chip on your shoulder you've always had.
-情况有多差  -很差
- How bad is it? - Bad.
他们拿到了确凿的证据
They got a smoking gun?
而且还有大王牌
And the bullet and the body, too.
那么你们打算怎么做
So what are you gonna do?
我们得先搞清楚发生了什么事
We're gonna find out what the hell's going on here.
那是什么
What is that?
我的辞职信
My letter of resignation.
我不会在这种人手下工作的
I'm not gonna work for a man like that.
-哪种人  -你在开玩笑吗
- A man like what? - Are you kidding me?
我知道你看见了
I know you saw that.
我不打算忍受疯子对我的欺凌
And I'm not gonna put up with being bullied by a nut job.
我没像别人那样起诉他  他该感到幸运
He's lucky I don't sue him like everybody else.
- 什么  - 我说他很幸运
- Excuse me? - I said, he's lucky
我没像其他人那样起诉他
I don't sue him like everybody else.
你知道吗  小喽
Well, you know what, you little pissant?
你何不试试呢
Why don't you go ahead and try?
因为他不费吹灰之力就能把无能的你
Because he will take your little incompetent ass
打败而大获全胜
and wipe the floor with you.
-什么  -你对我的误解
- What? - Oh, did you misunderstand me,
就如同你误解你的岗位一样
the way you misunderstood the assignment you were given?
因为也许你根本没有获得重视
Because maybe you weren't paying attention.
你辞职也许只能让律所损失一个客户而已
You may have just cost this firm a client.
胡说  他无权那样对待我
Bullshit. He had no right to treat me that way.
我不管他有没有权利
I don't give a shit what he had a right to.
如果你是我的儿子  我会告诉你
If you were my son, I would tell you
这是你自己的官司和乱子
this is your case and your mess.
我不是你的儿子  而且他把我赶走了
Well, I'm not your son. And he kicked me off.
与其像婴儿一样逃避
And instead of being a baby and running away,
身为男人会想办法留下并清除这乱子
a man would figure out a way to stay and clean up.
决定权在你
It's up to you.
但千万别再在我面前
But don't you dare talk shit about my boss
说我老板的闲话
to my face ever again.
我希望你们来告诉我此案
Well, I hope you're here to tell me the case
-将不予受理  -我们是来问你
- is getting dismissed. - We're here to ask you
你是否在公务便条上明确指示你的团队
if you wrote a memo instructing your team
要不惜一切卖掉那个部门
to sell that division for whatever it takes.
-不  我没有  - 那为什么
- No, I didn't. - Then why the hell
这报纸报道写着你有这么做
does the "Journal" Say you did?
-这太荒谬了  -之所以荒谬
- This is ridiculous. - Ridiculous because
是因为报道是假的还是你没写过便条
it isn't true or because you didn't write it?
-我没写过  -但这报道是真的
- I didn't write it. - But it is true.
我也许有提过如果能在年末前把一个部门
I may have mentioned it would be in our best interest
卖出去  对我们是最有利的
if a division was sold before the end of the year.
但我没有蠢到把这写到便条上
But I was never dumb enough to write it in a memo.
不  你就是蠢到把个人利益
No, you're just dumb enough to put your interests
-置于公司利益之上  -我代表公司
- in front of your company's. - I am this company.
我们的利益是一致的
Our interests are the same.
你们忘了你们是站在哪一边的吗
Or have you forgotten what side you're on?
我们一点都没忘
We haven't forgotten anything.
如果我们不了解全部实情就无法为你辩护
And we can't defend you if we don't have all the information.
那你现在了解了  我没有写过公务便条
Well now you have it. I didn't write the memo.
我没记错的话  是你们
And as I recall, you were the ones
刚过来敲我办公室的门
who came knocking on my door.
与其在半夜来我办公室
So instead of coming into my office in the middle
何不去做好你们的本分工作
of the night, why don't you do your job
防止这件事被置于法庭之上
and stop this goddamn thing from getting into court?
哈维  如果你打算告诉我
Harvey, if you're gonna tell me
你不相信她  那你可以省省了
you don't believe her, you can save it.
-我不打算那么说  -为什么
- I'm not gonna tell you that. - Why not?
因为但凡客户声明他们有罪
Because when a client says they're guilty,
我只相信他们说的那不是他们用的枪
I believe them when they say that's not the gun they used.
你想说什么
Then what were you gonna say?
我认为他把文件送来
I think he brought us that paper
让我们白跑一趟
to send us on a wild goose chase,
是想搞清楚备忘录的出处
trying to figure out where that memo came from.
他为什么要这么做
Why would he wanna do that?
因为事实上他没有备忘录
Because he doesn't actually have it.
并且想把我们的视线从球上移开
And he wanted to take our eyes off the ball.
我没听懂  什么球
I don't get it. What ball?
就是他会试图利用那篇文章作为证据
The ball that says he's gonna try and
得到他还未承认存在的
use that article as evidence to get the memo
-备忘录  -他不能这么做
- that he doesn't have admitted. - He can't do that.
根据举证规则  如果备忘录存在
The rules of evidence say that if that thing exists
但他没有原件  纳他连提交复印件的权利都没有
and he doesn't have it, he can't even submit a copy of it,
更别说提交提及它的一篇文章了
let alone an article referring to it.
哈维  他还想
And that, Harvey, is the ball he's trying
遮蔽我们的视线
to keep our eyes off of.
这意味着我们明天得在法庭上
That means all we have to do is show up at court tomorrow
-阻止他  -很棒  迈克
- and stop him. - That's pretty good, Mike.
我不得不赞叹一下
I gotta say, I'm impressed.
我也赞叹你记得举证规则
I'm impressed you remember the rules of evidence.
-我是一名律师  你知道的  -说实话
- I am a lawyer, you know. - To tell you the truth,
有那么一些瞬间
between the hair and the short hours,
我都有点忘记这事了
I kinda forget it sometimes.
我不懂这是什么意思
I don't even know what that means.
我很确定你知道这是什么意思
I'm pretty sure you know what that means.
-晚安  迈克  -晚安  哈维
- Good night, Michael. - Night, Harvey.
好了  我们来过一遍计划
Okay, let's go over the plan.
好  我们让所有的信贷员以为
Okay, we make every one of these loan officers
我们已经看过他们的记录
think that we've seen their records.
如果他们不愿承认所做所为是上级要求
And if they're not willing to admit this came from the top,
我们就证明这是他们自己的决定
we're gonna show that they did this all on their own.
如此一来  我们向住房和城市发展部举报他们
In which case, we report them to HUD
他们就永远无法在银行工作了
and they never work in banking again.
-很好  -好的
- Good. - Good.
上次我们俩像现在这样
You know, the last time we worked together
一起工作是在...
on something like this was...
你帮我参加模拟联合国的时候
When you helped me with Model U.N.
我那时还在瑞士
I was Switzerland.
据我回忆
And as I recall,
你在瑞士的时候可没这么厉害
Switzerland's never kicked so much ass.
我很高兴你推迟了婚礼
I'm glad you put off that wedding.
什么
What?
-我以为你喜欢迈克  -我喜欢
- I thought you liked Mike. - I do.
但你推迟婚礼把时间用在工作上
But you put it off to spend time on your career.
正因为此
And because of that,
我现在才能跟你共处
I'm spending time with you right now.
路易  我很高兴你在这里
Louis. I'm glad you're here.
我也很高兴你在这里  布莱恩  我...
I'm glad you're here, too. Brian, I--
-我想说声抱歉  -你不必道歉
- I wanna say I'm sorry. - You don't have to apologize.
你说得对
You were right.
我把案子搞砸了
I messed up the case.
但我想给你看这个
But I wanna show you this.
你怎么想到这个的
How'd you come up with this?
想听实话吗  我很生气
The truth? I was pissed off
然后我忍不住去想你如何用同样的方式
and I couldn't stop thinking about how you keep treating us
一次又一次地折磨我们
the same way over and over again.
然后我突然想到  大多数人都有固定模式
And then I got to thinking, most people have a pattern.
-大多数公司也是如此  -没错
- And most companies do, too. - Exactly.
布莱恩  这可是很大的工作量
Brian, this is an amazing amount of work.
我熬了一整夜完成的
I stayed up all night doing it.
但我以为你熬夜陪儿子去了
But I thought you take the night shift with your son.
通常是的  但我告诉我妻子
Usually, but I told my wife
昨晚她来接替我
she'd have to take it last night
因为我不想被人指责
because I don't like being accused
是一个糟糕的父亲
of being a bad father.
但我不能让这种恐惧导致我变成一个烂律师
But I won't abide it making me a bad lawyer.
我不明白
Uh, I don't understand.
这怎么会让你成为烂律师
How does that make you a bad lawyer?
我并不是说这是你的错
I am not saying that it's your fault.
但当我想象他嘲笑我时
But when I pictured him laughing at me,
我很失控
I lost control.
我写下了糟糕的话
And I wrote the word inferior
是因为我想攻击他
because I was lashing out at him.
因为事实是...
Because the truth is...
我害怕成为一个糟糕的父亲
I'm afraid I am a bad father.
你是个好父亲  布莱恩
You're a good father, Brian.
你怎么知道
How can you know that?
我就是知道  而且我还知道
Because I do, and I know what's it like
自己的不安全感妨碍了工作是什么感觉
to let your insecurities get in the way of your work,
相信我
believe me.
但现在  我们要从不安全感中
But right now, we're gonna channel the shit
走出来
out of our insecurities
然后去对付这些无耻的混蛋
and go spank these nipple-stealing motherfu--ers.
好吧
Okay.
法官  你给了我二十四小时
Your Honor, you gave me 24 hours to introduce evidence
为立案提交证据
that I have a case.
我想提交这个文件
Well, I would like to introduce this document.
法官  他想提交一篇文章
Your Honor, he's about to introduce
上面写着我的委托人
an article that says my client
主导了一次公司非法出售
directed an illegal sale of a company.
我手里就有一份这篇文章
Well, I have a copy of that article right here
除非他有文章提到的真实备忘录
and unless he has the actual memo it refers to,
否则这篇文章是不能采纳的
this article itself is inadmissible.
交给我看看
Let me see that.
法官  斯佩克特说得对
Your Honor, Mr. Specter's right,
我没有他口中的备忘录
I do not have the memo that he's referring to.
但既然他提起这个
But since he brought it up,
我想提交这篇文章的原因是  向法庭显示
the reason that I would like to have entered that article
该备忘录确实存在  并且他把它毁了
is to show the court that that memo existed and he buried it.
-什么  -马利克  这说法很离谱
- What? - Mr. Malik, that's an outrageous claim.
真正离谱的是他曾经也这么做
What's outrageous is that he's done it before
现在却依旧是律师
and he's still practicing law.
好吧  你这是撒谎  我想要这段话
Okay, that is a lie and I want that
-做无效处理  -这不是撒谎
- stricken from the record. - It's not a lie.
-我有证据  -鬼扯
- I can prove it. - Bullshit.
斯佩克特  够了
Mr. Specter, that's enough.
如果马利克无法证实他的主张
If Mr. Malik can't back up his allegation,
他会被指控藐视法庭
he'll be held in contempt of court.
但依据我的经验  老狗学不了新把戏
But in my experience, old dogs don't learn new tricks.
所以如果他能证明  再加上这篇文章
So if he can prove it, that combined with this article
我有理由相信你又故技重施
will give me reason to believe that you've done it again.
两天后开庭
We'll reconvene in two days.
他在说些什么
What the hell is he talking about?
无论如何  我向你保证
Whatever it is, I swear to you
等尘埃落定  我们会赢得庭审
that when the dust settles, we'll still win this thing.
混蛋  你才没有证据
You son of a bitch. You got nothing on me
因为我没做过
because there's nothing to have.
我证据多的是  唯一的问题是
Oh, I've got plenty. The only question is,
在你多次越界行为中
which one of the many times that you've crossed the line
我该对外揭露哪一次
am I planning on exposing to the world?
我希望你不会介意  我是在投桃报李
I hope you don't mind. I'm returning the favor.
你最好别在这里吼我
You better not be in here to yell at me.
我不会的  我来这里告诉你你说对了
I'm not. I'm here to tell you that you were right.
我很抱歉吼了你  格蕾琴
And I'm sorry I yelled at you, Gretchen.
我还很抱歉让你取消利普希茨的预约
And I'm also sorry I told you to cancel Lipschitz.
这是我说过最蠢的话了
I mean, that was the dumbest thing I've ever said.
不  路易  你说过最蠢的话是
No, Louis, the dumbest thing you've ever said
你叫我在办公室
was when you ordered me to adopt
养一窝暹罗猫
a family of Siamese cats for the office.
但你没有这样做
But you didn't do that.
我也没有取消利普希茨的预约
And I didn't cancel Lipschitz either.
我把时间改到了今晚六点
I moved him to 6:00 tonight.
六点  我不可能赶得上  现在太晚了
6? I'll never make it over there, it's too late.
所以庆幸的是我说服他到这里来
Then it's a good thing I convinced him to come here.
谢谢你  格雷琴
Thank you, Gretchen.
还有  我绝不会开除你
And for the record, I would never fire you.
我知道  路易
I know, Louis.
我知道
I know.
-戴维斯小姐  -你看起来很惊讶
- Ms. Davies? - You look surprised.
我们准时到了  对吧
We have the time right, don't we?
是的
Yes, you do.
我们开始前  我想指出
Before we get started, I would just like to point out
我们不仅要为我们的客户讨回公道
we're not just here to get justice for our clients.
我们还会保护你
We're also here to protect you.
小心  丽莎  他们试图博得你的信任
Careful, Lisa, they're trying to get your trust
然后在背后捅你一刀
before they stab you in the back.
-我们不会捅任何人  -我们有123个起诉人
- We're not stabbing anyone. - We have 123 plaintiffs
被操控负担更高的贷款汇率
who were all steered into higher rate mortgages
这些人都恰好是有色人种
all of whom happen to be people of color.
你的问题到底是什么
And what exactly is your question?
我们想知道谁给了你的客户这样的授权
We wanna know who gave your client the goddamn mandate.
-没有什么授权  -没有写到纸上
- There is no mandate. - Just because it's not
并不意味着没法想明白
written down doesn't mean it's not understood.
我在雅芳做了十年的信贷员
I've been a loan officer at Avon for ten years.
我们的贷款流程不允许出现歧视
Our lending process doesn't allow for discrimination.
-怎么可能  -一个电脑程序
- How is that possible? - A computer program
在准批人员看到申请之前
strips out race, gender, and photos
剔除种族  性别和照片信息
before approval officers ever see the application.
胡说  那为什么一开始要
Bullshit. Then why even ask for those things
-这些信息呢  -因为我们要防止
- in the first place? - Because we have to protect
-身份欺诈  -这些都没有阻止
against identity fraud. - And none of that
老板让你们拒绝512个人的
stops the boss from telling you to deny number 512
合法贷款
their rightful mortgage.
因为他是可恶的掠夺者
Because he's a predatory piece of shit
他用你这样的傻瓜打掩护
and he's using fools like you to cover his own ass!
-你说什么  -爸
- Excuse me? - Dad.
你怎么能为这样的人工作
How can you work for a man like that?
我绝不会在一个
I would never work for a place
有歧视的地方工作而且我很乐意
that engaged in discrimination and I am more than happy
-在法庭上这么说  -你会有机会的
- to say that on the stand. - Well, you're gonna
因为这里面有猫腻
get your chance because something is going on here
我会查到底
and I'm gonna get to the bottom of this.
-我们谈完了  -胡说  还没完
- We're done here. - Bullshit, we're done.
我们还有五个人要取证
We have five more people to depose.
他们会说和丽莎同样的话
And they're gonna say the exact same thing Lisa just did,
但我不会给你机会像你对待她一样
but I'm not gonna give you the chance to treat them
对待他们
the way you just treated her.
我会请愿法官
What I am gonna do is petition the judge
废掉这个案子
to have this case thrown out.
别告诉我你还想让我放弃
Don't tell me you still want me to give up
因为即使我想...
because even if I wanted to--
这不是我要说的
That's not what I'm here to say.
我们得弄明白他说的是哪个案子
We need to figure out what case he's talking about.
我知道哪个案子  他在地检办公室工作了十年
I know what case. He worked in the DA's office ten years.
他说的是克利福德・丹纳
He's talking about Clifford Danner.
哈维  这讲不通
Harvey, that doesn't make any sense.
你没有压着证据  那是卡梅隆・丹尼斯
You didn't suppress that evidence, Cameron Dennis did.
马利克才不管
Malik doesn't give a shit about that.
我是当时的检察官
I was the prosecuting attorney.
我应该知道自己案子的情况
I should've known what was happening with my own case,
意味着我们完了
which means we're screwed.
-除非...  -除非什么
- Unless-- - Unless what?
除非我们能让卡梅隆・丹尼斯承认
Unless we can get Cameron Dennis to admit
他隐藏了证据而你不知道
that he buried the evidence and that you didn't know about it.
迈克  卡梅隆才不会承认
Mike, there's no way Cameron's gonna admit to that.
-等等  -什么
- Wait a second. - What?
他也不能因为我没有做的事情
There's also no way he'd set me up
陷害我
for something I didn't do.
所以我们得找出马利克会怎样做
Which means we need to figure out how Malik's
看起来像是我隐藏了证据
gonna make it look like I suppressed that evidence.
他会传唤你办克利福德・丹纳时的
He's gonna subpoena the one other person who was there
另一个人
when you put Clifford Danner away.
-不  -他打给我要
- No. - Yes. He's calling me
两天后出庭
to the stand in two days.
我们得帮你准备好
Then we need to get you prepared.
我们得在大庭广众下做
And we need to do it in front of an audience.
你指的是模拟庭审吗
You're talking about a mock trial?
不行  我不会让唐娜这样
No way, I'm not putting Donna through that.
哈维  迈克说得对
Harvey, Mike's right.
但你不是那个让我承受这些的人
But you're not the one who has to put me through it,
-必须是路易  -唐娜
- it has to be Louis. - Donna,
你知道上次路易这么做的时候发生了什么
you know what happened last time Louis did that.
我知道  他很残忍
Yes, I do. He was brutal.
正是安德・马利克要做的
Which is exactly what Andy Malik's gonna be.
所以要么你告诉路易  要么我去
So either you can tell Louis or I will.
不管怎样  必须是他
But either way, it's gotta be him.
唐娜  即使我同意
Donna, even if I said yes,
上次路易这么做  他很难受
last time Louis did that, it made him sick.
他不会再想这样做的
He's not gonna wanna do that again.
他不会愿意
He won't want to.
但是他会做
But he will.
感谢抽空见我
Well, thanks for meeting me here.
当你推迟了我们的治疗
Well, when you put off our session,
我知道你一定在忙要紧的事
I knew you must be in the middle of something important.
不是因为这个
That's not why I put it off.
发生了什么  路易
What happened, Louis?
你还记得希拉吗
You remember Sheila?
当然
Yeah, of course.
她是我们多次谈话的主角
She was the subject of many of our conversations.
总而言之  她要结婚了
Yeah, well the long and short of it is she's getting married.
在她结婚之前  她想和我
And before she does, she wanted to have
共度最后一晚
one last night with me.
我没有告诉你
And I didn't tell you about it
是因为我怕你批判我
because I was afraid that you would judge me.
路易  我怎么看你的行为不重要
Louis, it doesn't matter what I think of your actions.
你怎么看
What do you think?
她说这会让她解脱开始新生活
She said it would free her to live her life.
我想让她快乐地生活
And I want her to be happy with her life,
即使不是和我
even if it's not with me.
那么你的出发点是对的
Then your heart is in the right place.
看到了吗  我的出发点不是问题
Don't you see? My heart is not the problem.
我不能忘掉她
I can't get her out of my head.
希拉
It's Sheila.
一直都是希拉
It's always been Sheila.
但是路易  我记得
But Louis, as I recall,
是你和她提出分手
it was you who ended it with her.
因为我想要孩子
Because I wanted to have a baby.
她不想
And she didn't.
而现在我什么都没有了
And now I'm not gonna have anything.
路易  我都明白
Louis, I understand all that.
但是根据格雷琴告诉我的情况
But from what Gretchen told me,
我想是时候想办法
I think it's time we figure out a way
防止你向周围的人出气了
for you to stop lashing out at those around you.
我以为你回办公室去了
I thought you went back to your office.
没有  我想给你一些时间
No, I didn't. I thought that I would
冷静下来之后
give you some time to calm down
告诉我实话
and think about telling me the truth
这是怎么一回事
about what is going on here.
没怎么回事
Nothing's going on.
爸  你说你想和我
Dad, you said that you wanted
更亲近
to be closer with me.
现在就是你的机会
Now's your chance.
这个案子无关乎种族或钱
This case isn't about race or money.
掌管这家公司的人是个彻彻底底的
That man who heads up this company is a predator,
掠夺者
through and through.
我想教训他因为有个人
And I wanted to get him back for going after
我曾有机会去帮助
the one person I should've helped when I had the chance.
却没有
But I didn't.
谁
Who?
25年前  那位总裁还是个分店经理
25 years ago, that CEO was a branch manager.
阿瑟・克特里奇
Arthur Kitridge.
你姑姑为他工作过
And your aunt worked for him.
他把她的生活变成了地狱
And he made her life a living hell.
因为她是黑人吗
Because she was black?
因为她是个美人
Because she was beautiful.
他不断骚扰她
He wouldn't leave her alone.
最终  她威胁说要告他
Finally, she threatened to do something,
就被他解雇了
and he fired her.
而你没有帮她
And you didn't help her.
当时我只是个刚出道的律师
I was a young attorney.
接这种案子
Taking on a case like that
只会让我自己也丢了工作
was only gonna get me fired, too.
所以我告诉她我们没有办法
So I told her there was nothing we could do.
那之后
And after that...
她的生活就分崩离析了
her life fell apart.
爸爸  你为什么从来没跟我说过
Dad, why didn't you ever tell me any of this before?
因为几年后
Because she died
她就去世了  而我一直很羞愧
a few years later, and I was ashamed.
接着当我看到你未婚夫冒着被解雇的危险
And then I watched your fiancé risk his career
去帮那些囚犯
to help those prisoners
我就知道我该做些什么了
and I knew I had to do something.
你只见过后来的她
You only knew her later.
如果你认识以前那个
But if you had seen her before,
聪明  美丽  充满活力的她
smart, beautiful, full of life...
她的未来本来有无限可能
she could've been anything she wanted.
像你一样
Just like you.
我也希望能认识当时的她
I wish I had known her then.
但是爸爸  我知道一旦你决定做一件事
But Dad, I know that whenever you set your mind to something,
就没有什么能阻碍你
there is nothing that can stop you.
所以我建议我们今晚好好整顿
So I say we take the night and we regroup.
明天早上  我们一定能想到办法
And tomorrow morning, we'll find a way.
-路易  等等  -不管是什么事
- Louis, wait. - Whatever it is, guys,
我可以明天做  今天我心情不好
I can deal with it tomorrow. It's been an emotional day.
很遗憾  必须今天说
Unfortunately, it's not over yet.
首席检察官
I've been subpoenaed
给我发了传票
by the Attorney General's office.
什么  你跟哈维的案子
What are you talking about? You have nothing to do
-又没关系  -是没有
- with Harvey's case. - She doesn't.
但他想利用她
But he wants to use her to prove
证明我以前隐藏过证据
that I've suppressed evidence before
而我现在正故伎重演
and I'm doing it again.
-你有过吗  -没有
- Did you? - No.
路易  他要问我克利福德・丹纳案
Louis, he's gonna question me about the Clifford Danner case
他会故意把这事说得好像哈维本已知情
and try to make it look like Harvey knew what was going on
所以我肯定也知道
and so I must've too.
你知道这意味着什么  我需要你帮我准备
You know what that means. I need you to prepare me.
我不管
I don't care.
-我做不到  -路易
- I can't. - Louis.
不行  去找亚历克斯  或者迈克
No. Ask Alex to do it, ask Mike.
必须是你  你以前也做过
It has to be you, you've done it before.
所以我才不想再来一次
Which is exactly why I don't wanna do it again.
-我不想这样对唐娜  -路易
- I'm not doing that to Donna. - Louis.
你当时跟我说你之所以那么做
Look, you told me you did what you did
是因为特拉维斯・坦纳不在乎唐娜
because Travis Tanner doesn't give a shit about Donna
他会尽其所能击溃她
and he was gonna come after her full bore.
这个人一样冷酷无情
Well, this guy has at least as much of an axe to grind.
他还和我们一起在检察院公事过
And he worked with us in the D.A.'s office.
也就是说他了解我们
Which means he knows more about us.
而保护我的唯一办法  就是你帮我准备好
And the only way to protect me is to prepare me
怎么应付这场战斗
for what's coming.
你又要我进行人身攻击
You are asking me to go personal again.
-我不要  -不  路易
- And I won't do it. - No. Louis,
我是在要你再次  不择手段地
I am asking you to do whatever you have to do
保护我
to protect me again.
而且你这么做不是坏事
And I am telling you it's okay to do it.
好吧
Okay.
但是这些都得等明天
But I'm not gonna do anything until tomorrow.
有一件事必须先办
Because I need to do something first.
唐娜  你怎么来了
Donna, what are you doing here?
我准备好告诉你那天
I'm ready to tell you about what happened
我约会的事了
on my date the other night.
迈克还在办公室
Well, Mike's still at the office
家里只有我们两个  说吧
and we've got the place all to ourselves, so...
你还记得几年前哈维的
Do you remember at Harvey's mock trial
模拟庭审上  路易问我是不是爱着哈维吗
a couple years ago when Louis asked if I loved Harvey?
怎么会忘
How could I not?
他还问到了我上一段认真的恋情
And he also asked me about my last serious boyfriend
为何结束
and what broke us up.
他要求你在他
He asked you to choose
和哈维之间做选择
between him and Harvey.
你不愿意
And you wouldn't.
最近我想起了这个前任
Well, I was thinking about that old boyfriend recently
于是
and...
我叫他出来吃了午餐
I called him and we went out to lunch.
-然后呢  -很棒
- And? - It was wonderful.
知道他跟我说他结婚了
Until he told me he was married.
当时接到你的短信时  我正要
And I was about to meet him at a hotel
去旅馆见他
when I got your text.
我跟他说我做不到
And I told him I couldn't.
你怎么不早点告诉我
Why didn't you tell me about any of this earlier?
我不知道  我想也许是我在自责
I don't know. I guess maybe I was judging myself
我害怕你也会指责我
and I was afraid that you were gonna judge me, too.
-我不会的  -我知道
- I would never do that. - I know.
但有时候拒绝别人的关心
But sometimes it's just easier to push away the people
比实话实说要容易
who care about you than tell them the real story.
好吧
Well,
不管你怎么推开我
you can push me away as much as you want.
我都不会抛弃你的
I'll still be here.
你后悔吗
Do you regret it?
后悔什么
Regret what?
把哈维置于这个人之上
Putting Harvey over this guy.
我想我后悔的  也许是把哈维置于我自己之上
I think maybe I regret putting Harvey over myself.
路易  半夜十一点  你怎么来了
Louis, what are you doing here? 11:00 P.M.
我来是因为我知道你晚上要照顾他
I came because I knew you were taking the night shift
但你昨晚都没有睡觉
and since you stayed up all last night,
所以我想也许你需要点帮助
I thought you might need a little relief.
真的吗
Are you sure?
真的  虽然前半个小时
I am. Though I may need a little help
可能还需要你指导
with the first half hour.
不用吧  我觉得你天生就会
I don't know, you look like a natural to me.
-要抱抱他吗  -好
- You wanna take him? - Yeah.
好的
Okay.
-托住他的头  -头  好的
- Oh, get his head. - His head, okay.
-头要托稳  -好的
- You gotta support his head. - There we go.
奥斯汀  这是路易
Austin, I'd like you to meet Louis.
奥斯汀  很高兴认识你
Austin, it's so nice to meet you.
快请进
Hey, come in.
你真的觉得我天生就会吗
Do you really think I'm gonna be a natural?
当然
Yeah, absolutely.
现在做什么
Oh, what do I do?
我不管了  我睡了
I don't care. I'm going to sleep.
不行不行  我不知道该做什么
Oh, no, no, no, no. What do I do?
谢啦
Thank you.
不会有事的
It's gonna be okay.
你好  我叫路易
Hello. I'm Louis.